<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Big Data on Michael Skirpan&#39;s Personal Webpage</title>
    <link>http://mwskirpan.com/tags/big-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Big Data on Michael Skirpan&#39;s Personal Webpage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mwskirpan.com/tags/big-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyday Data: An Interactive Data Installation in CU-Boulder&#39;s ATLAS Lobby Space</title>
      <link>http://mwskirpan.com/blog/atlas_installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mwskirpan.com/blog/atlas_installation/</guid>
      <description>In the Autumn of 2014, with the hard work of the students in our HCC: Big Data class, I mentored them in creating lobby art installation that combined both the technical and aesthetic aspects of large-scale data collection. The installation was the culminating project of our upper-division class on the subject, and its implementation was supported generously by a grant from CU-Boulder&amp;rsquo;s Engineering Excellence Fund along with my advisor Tom Yeh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>atlas_expo</title>
      <link>http://mwskirpan.com/extras/traffic_monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 15:17:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mwskirpan.com/extras/traffic_monitor/</guid>
      <description>The Bit-Wise Soul of the 21st Century The objective of this project was to create a compelling experience from data coming from sensors placed under mats at the entrance of CU&amp;rsquo;s Atlas lobby. Every ten minutes, the sensor count resets. The balls on the screen represent the number of times the sensor has been hit since th last reset. The bottom left times represent sensor counts from previous hours and bottom-right times represent predictions for the next two hours based on the average from past days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>